<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Example Projects :: CIS 526 Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/</link><description>Example projects you can follow along with!</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Express Starter Project</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/01-express-starter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/01-express-starter/</guid><description>This example project is the first in a series toward building a complete full-stack web application using Node.js and Express to create a RESTful API on the backend that connects to a database, and then a Vue single page application on the frontend.
In doing so, we’ll explore some of the standard ways web developers use existing tools, frameworks, and libraries to perform many of the operations we’ve learned how to do manually throughout this course.</description></item><item><title>Adding a Database</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/02-database/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/02-database/</guid><description>This example project builds on the previous Express Starter Project by adding a database. A database is a powerful way to store and retrieve the data used by our web application.
To accomplish this, we’ll learn about different libraries that interface between our application and a database. Once we’ve installed a library, we’ll discover how to use that library to create database tables, add initial data to those tables, and then easily access them within our application.</description></item><item><title>RESTful API</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/03-rest-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/03-rest-api/</guid><description>This example project builds on the previous Adding a Database project by using that project to create a RESTful API. That API can be used to access and modify the data in the database. We’ll also add a suite of unit tests to explore our API and ensure that it is working correctly.
Project Deliverables At the end of this example, we will have a project with the following features:</description></item><item><title>Authentication</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/04-authentication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/04-authentication/</guid><description>This example project builds on the previous RESTful API project by adding user authentication. This will ensure users are identified within the system and are only able to perform operations according to the roles assigned to their user accounts.
Project Deliverables At the end of this example, we will have a project with the following features:
An authentication system using Passport.js and CAS Valid JSON Web Tokens (JWTs) for authentication within the RESTful API Proper middleware to verify users have the correct role for each operation in the API Prior Work This project picks up right where the last one left off, so if you haven’t completed that one yet, go back and do that before starting this one.</description></item><item><title>Vue.js Starter Project</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/05-vue-starter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/05-vue-starter/</guid><description>This example project builds on the previous RESTful API project by scaffolding a frontend application using Vue.js. This will become the basis for a full frontend for the application over the next few projects.
Project Deliverables At the end of this example, we will have a project with the following features:
A single page frontend application running in Vue 3. Built-in Vue features such as Vue Router and Pinia. Access to components and icons from PrimeVue.</description></item><item><title>Vue.js CRUD App</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/06-vue-crud-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/06-vue-crud-app/</guid><description>This example project builds on the previous Vue.js starter project by scaffolding a CRUD frontend for the basic users and roles tables.
Project Deliverables At the end of this example, we will have a project with the following features:
Prior Work This project picks up right where the last one left off, so if you haven’t completed that one yet, go back and do that before starting this one.
Let’s get started!</description></item><item><title>Vue.js Components</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/07-vue-components/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/07-vue-components/</guid><description>This example project builds on the previous Vue.js CRUD app by building a few custom components to view and update data in the application.
Project Deliverables At the end of this example, we will have a project with the following features:
Prior Work This project picks up right where the last one left off, so if you haven’t completed that one yet, go back and do that before starting this one.</description></item></channel></rss>