<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Example Projects :: CIS 526 Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/index.html</link><description>Example projects you can follow along with!</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Express Starter Project</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/01-express-starter/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/01-express-starter/index.html</guid><description>This example project is the first in a series toward building a complete full-stack web application using Node.js and Express to create a RESTful API on the backend that connects to a database, and then a Vue single page application on the frontend.
In doing so, we’ll explore some of the standard ways web developers use existing tools, frameworks, and libraries to perform many of the operations we’ve learned how to do manually throughout this course. In essence, you’ve already learned how to build these things from scratch, but now we’ll look at how professionals use dependencies to accomplish many of the same things.</description></item><item><title>Adding a Database</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/02-database/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/02-database/index.html</guid><description>This example project builds on the previous Express Starter Project by adding a database. A database is a powerful way to store and retrieve the data used by our web application.
To accomplish this, we’ll learn about different libraries that interface between our application and a database. Once we’ve installed a library, we’ll discover how to use that library to create database tables, add initial data to those tables, and then easily access them within our application.</description></item><item><title>RESTful API</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/03-rest-api/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/03-rest-api/index.html</guid><description>This example project builds on the previous Adding a Database project by using that project to create a RESTful API. That API can be used to access and modify the data in the database. We’ll also add a suite of unit tests to explore our API and ensure that it is working correctly.
Project Deliverables At the end of this example, we will have a project with the following features:
A RESTful API with several routes for creating, reading, updating, and deleting (CRUD) data in the database Open API Documentation for API Routes Full Unit Test Suite with Coverage Metrics Prior Work This project picks up right where the last one left off, so if you haven’t completed that one yet, go back and do that before starting this one.</description></item><item><title>Authentication</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/04-authentication/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/04-authentication/index.html</guid><description>This example project builds on the previous RESTful API project by adding user authentication. This will ensure users are identified within the system and are only able to perform operations according to the roles assigned to their user accounts.
Project Deliverables At the end of this example, we will have a project with the following features:
An authentication system using Passport.js and CAS Valid JSON Web Tokens (JWTs) for authentication within the RESTful API Proper middleware to verify users have the correct role for each operation in the API Prior Work This project picks up right where the last one left off, so if you haven’t completed that one yet, go back and do that before starting this one.</description></item><item><title>Vue.js Starter Project</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/05-vue-starter/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/05-vue-starter/index.html</guid><description>This example project builds on the previous RESTful API project by scaffolding a frontend application using Vue.js. This will become the basis for a full frontend for the application over the next few projects.
Project Deliverables At the end of this example, we will have a project with the following features:
A single page frontend application running in Vue 3. Built-in Vue features such as Vue Router and Pinia. Access to components and icons from PrimeVue. Access to Tailwind CSS for additional CSS styling and features. A working Dark Mode Theme completed with a selector that remembers our preference. A working Vite server that will proxy requests to our backend RESTful API seamlessly. An Axios client that can access our RESTful API routes. A seamless system for authentication and requesting a JWT to access protected API routes. Prior Work This project picks up right where the last one left off, so if you haven’t completed that one yet, go back and do that before starting this one.</description></item><item><title>Vue.js CRUD App</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/06-vue-crud-app/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/06-vue-crud-app/index.html</guid><description>This example project builds on the previous Vue.js starter project by scaffolding a CRUD frontend for the basic users and roles tables.
Project Deliverables At the end of this example, we will have a project with the following features:
Most menu items and routes are protected and only allow users with specific roles to view/access them A page that lists all roles in the application for anyone with the manage_users role. Roles are not editable. A page that lists all users in a data table for anyone with the manage_users role. Helpful Columns on that page should be searchable and sortable, as well as the ability to filter by role A page to edit existing users, including updating their roles A page to create new users and assign new roles A method to delete existing users Prior Work This project picks up right where the last one left off, so if you haven’t completed that one yet, go back and do that before starting this one.</description></item><item><title>Advanced Topics</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/07-advanced-topics/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/07-advanced-topics/index.html</guid><description>This example project builds on the previous Vue.js CRUD app by discussing some more advanced topics related to web application development.
Project Deliverables At the end of this example, we will have a project with the following features:
A Pinia store that handles storing users and roles, and all Vue components adapted to use that Pinia store A DynamicDialog for editing and creating users, which repurposes the UserEdit component A working Dockerfile for the project A working GitHub Action to build the Docker image and release it on GitHub A working Docker Compose file to deploy the application The application is adapted to optionally use Postgres instead of SQLite as the database engine Prior Work This project picks up right where the last one left off, so if you haven’t completed that one yet, go back and do that before starting this one.</description></item><item><title>Errata</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/08-errata/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-examples/08-errata/index.html</guid><description>This page lists all of the errors found and updates I have made to the basic project since this was released.
Client Update Token Store In my Vue code, I was often using tokenStore.token.length > 0 to determine if a user was logged in. This is a bit fragile - better to just make a computed value for this:
​ client/src/stores/Token.js // Getters const loggedIn = computed(() => token.value.length > 0 ) This requires changing several other places in ths code where this is used - mainly I just searched for token.length and went from there.</description></item></channel></rss>