<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>JavaScript :: CIS 526 Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/c-js/index.html</link><description>Bringing interaction to web pages since 1995.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 14:51:29 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/c-js/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/c-js/01-introduction/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/c-js/01-introduction/index.html</guid><description>As the World Wide Web was gaining popularity in the mid-nineties, browser manufacturers started experimenting with interpreting program scripts embedded within webpages. By far the most successful of these was JavaScript, initally developed by Brandon Eich for Netscape.
Brandon Eich was hired to integrate the Scheme programming langauge into the Netscape browser. But when Netscape cut a deal with Sun Microsystems to bring Java Applets to their browser, his mission was altered to create a more Java-like langauge. He developed a prototype in only ten days, that blended Java syntax, the Self object-orientation approach, and Scheme functionality.</description></item><item><title>Basic Syntax</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/c-js/02-basic-syntax/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/c-js/02-basic-syntax/index.html</guid><description>CONSOLE Because Netscape was adopting Java at the same time they were developing what would become JavaScript, there was a push to make the syntax stay somewhat consistent between the two languages. As a result, JavaScript has much of the look and feel of an imperative language like C, C#, or Java.</description></item><item><title>JavaScript Functions</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/c-js/03-functions/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/c-js/03-functions/index.html</guid><description>CONSOLE While JavaScript may look like an imperative language on the surface, much of how it behaves is based on functional languages like Scheme. This leads to some of the common sources of confusion for programmers new to the language. Let’s explore just what its functional roots mean.</description></item><item><title>Arrays - Lists by Another Name</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/c-js/04-arrays-and-lists/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/c-js/04-arrays-and-lists/index.html</guid><description>CONSOLE You might have noticed we used an array in discussing the for .. in loop, but didn’t talk about it in our data type discussion. This is because in JavaScript, an array is not a primitive data type. Rather, it’s a special kind of object.</description></item><item><title>Objects and Classes</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/c-js/05-objects-and-classes/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/c-js/05-objects-and-classes/index.html</guid><description>CONSOLE JavaScript is also an object-oriented language, but the way it implements objects is derived from the ideas of the Self programming language, rather than the C++ origins of Java and C#’s object-oriented approaches.</description></item><item><title>Attaching Scripts</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/c-js/06-attaching-scripts/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/c-js/06-attaching-scripts/index.html</guid><description>Much like there are multiple ways to apply CSS to a web app, there are multiple ways to bring JavaScript into one. We can use a &lt;script> tag with a specified src attribute to load a separate document, put our code into the &lt;script> tag directly, or even add code to attributes of an HTML element. Let’s look at each option.
Script Tag with Source We can add a &lt;script> tag with a src attribute that gives a url pointing to a JavaScript file. This is similar to how we used the &lt;link> element for CSS:</description></item><item><title>The Document Object Model</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/c-js/07-the-dom/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/c-js/07-the-dom/index.html</guid><description>Now that we’ve reviewed the basic syntax and structure of the JavaScript language, and how to load it into a page, we can turn our attention to what it was created for - to interact with web pages in the browser. This leads us to the Document Object Model (DOM).
The DOM is a tree-like structure that is created by the browser when it parses the HTML page. Then, as CSS rules are interpreted and applied, they are attached to the individual nodes of the tree. Finally, as the page’s JavaScript executes, it may modify the tree structure and node properties. The browser uses this structure and properties as part of its rendering process.</description></item><item><title>Strict Mode</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/c-js/08-strict-mode/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/c-js/08-strict-mode/index.html</guid><description>JavaScript has been around a long time, and a lot of JavaScript code has been written by inexperienced programmers. Browser manufacturers compensated for this by allowing lenient interpretation of JavaScript programs, and by ignoring many errors as they occurred.
While this made poorly-written scripts run, arguably they didn’t run well. In ECMA5, strict mode was introduced to solve the problems of lenient interpretation.
Strict mode according to the Mozilla Developer Network:</description></item><item><title>Regular Expressions</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/c-js/09-regexp/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/c-js/09-regexp/index.html</guid><description>CONSOLE The JavaScript String prototype has some very powerful methods, such as String.prototype.includes() which recognizes when a string contains a substring - i.e.:</description></item><item><title>JSON</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/c-js/10-json/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/c-js/10-json/index.html</guid><description>JSON is an acronym for JavaScript Object Notation, a serialization format that was developed in conjunction with ECMAScript 3. It is a standard format, as set by ECMA-404.
JSON Format Essentially, it is a format for transmitting JavaScript objects. Consider the JavaScript object literal notation:
var wilma = { name: "Wilma Flintstone", relationship: "wife" } var pebbles = { name: "Pebbles Flintstone", age: 3, relationship: "daughter" } var fred = { name: "Fred Flintstone", job: "Quarry Worker", payRate: 8, dependents: [wilma, pebbles] } If we were to express the same object in JSON:</description></item><item><title>AJAX</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/c-js/11-ajax/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/c-js/11-ajax/index.html</guid><description>Asynchronous JavaScript and XML (AJAX) is a term coined by Jesse James Garrett to describe a technique of using the XMLHttpRequest object to request resources directly from JavaScript. As the name implies, this was originally used to request XML content, but the technique can be used with any kind of data.
The XMLHttpRequest The XMLHttpRequest object is modeled after how the window object makes web requests. You can think of it as a state machine that can be in one of several possible states, defined by both a constant and an unsigned short value:</description></item></channel></rss>