<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>




	
	
			

	
	
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			
			

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Persistent Storage on CIS 526 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/07-persistent-storage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Persistent Storage on CIS 526 Textbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/07-persistent-storage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/07-persistent-storage/01-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/07-persistent-storage/01-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Of course, what made dynamic web servers interesting was that they could provide content built dynamically. In this approach, the HTML the server sends as a response does not need to be stored on the server as a HTML file, rather it can be constructed when a request is made.
That said, most web applications still need a persistent storage mechanism to use in dynamically creating those pages. If we&amp;rsquo;re dealing with a forum, we need to store the text for the posts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Serialization</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/07-persistent-storage/02-data-serialization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/07-persistent-storage/02-data-serialization/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps the simplest persistent storage mechanism we can adopt is to use a combination of an in-memory variable and a file. For example, we could set up a simple database mechanism as a Node module:
const fs = require(&amp;#39;fs&amp;#39;); /** @module database * A simple in-memory database implementation, * providing a mechanism for getting and saving * a database object */ module.exports = { get, set }; // We retrieve and deserialize the database from // a file named data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Databases</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/07-persistent-storage/03-databases/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/07-persistent-storage/03-databases/</guid>
      <description>As we suggested in the previous section, using an already existing database application is a very common strategy for full-stack web development. Doing so has clear benefits - such programs are typically stable, secure, and optimized for data storage and retrieval. They are well beyond what we can achieve ourselves without a significant investment of time, and avoids the necessity of &amp;ldquo;reinventing the wheel&amp;rdquo;.
That said, making effective use of a third-party database system does require you to develop familiarity with how the database operates and is organized.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relational Databases</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/07-persistent-storage/04-relational-databases/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/07-persistent-storage/04-relational-databases/</guid>
      <description>Relational databases (also called SQL databases) provide a highly-structured storage mechanism. Data is organized into tables, with each column representing a single value and data type, and each row representing one entry. Conceptually, this organization is similar to tables you have seen in Excel and on the web. An example persons table is listed below:
id First Last 0 Lisa Merkowsky 1 Frank Stiles 3 Mary Cotts Relational databases are often called SQL databases as we use Structured Query Language (SQL) to communicate with them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQL Injection</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/07-persistent-storage/05-sql-injection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/07-persistent-storage/05-sql-injection/</guid>
      <description>Along with the use of relational databases and SQL comes one very important attack to be aware of - SQL injection. This attack takes advantage of the way many developers write SQL queries within their programs. Consider the simple relational database we laid out earlier. Let&amp;rsquo;s assume our web application lets us search for people by their last names. To find Mary Cotts, we would then need a SQL query like:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Object-Relational Mapping</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/07-persistent-storage/06-orm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/07-persistent-storage/06-orm/</guid>
      <description>If you think learning and writing SQL looks challenging, you&amp;rsquo;re not alone. Early full-stack developers did as well. In addition, there was the additional need to convert the responses from the relational database from text into objects the program could use. It shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprising that libraries quickly were adopted to manage this process. The most basic of these are drivers, simple programs which manage the connection between the database and the program using it, sending SQL queries to the database and parsing the results into data types native to the language (usually an array of arrays or an array of dictionaries - the outer array for the rows, and the inner array or dictionary for the column values within the row).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>