<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Milestones :: CIS 526 Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-milestones/</link><description>Class Project Milestones!</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-milestones/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Express Starter Project</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-milestones/01-starter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-milestones/01-starter/</guid><description>This set of milestones is all about building a RESTful API and interface for the Lost Kansas Communities project.
Milestone 1 - Express Starter Project Follow the instructions in the Example Project to build a project using Node.js and Express that includes the following features:
A working GitHub Codespace containing Node.js A bare-bones Express application Update the Express application from CommonJS to ES Modules Application logs with Winston and Morgan Install other useful Express libraries like compression and helmet Install and configure Nodemon Install and configure dotenvx Create code documentation with JSDoc and OpenAPI comments Enable linting and formatting with ESLint and Prettier Effectively, just follow along with the example project and submit the resulting repository.</description></item><item><title>Add a Database</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-milestones/02-database/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/x-milestones/02-database/</guid><description>This set of milestones is all about building a RESTful API and interface for the Lost Kansas Communities project.
Milestone 2 - Add a Database Building from the previous milestone, expand upon the starter project by adding the following features:
Create an SQLite database Install and configure the Sequelize ORM and the Umzug migration tool Configure an automated process to migrate and seed the data on application startup Create database migrations, seeds, and models matching the database diagram given below Database Diagram Seed Data Seed data is stored in CSV files that can be downloaded from Canvas.</description></item></channel></rss>