




	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Announcements on CIS 526 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Announcements on CIS 526 Textbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:53:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spring &#39;23 Week 1</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week01/</guid>
      <description>Resources Slides Video Script Unknown Speaker 0:05
Hello, and welcome to the week one announcements video for CC 515 in spring 2023. My name is Russell Feldhausen. And I&amp;rsquo;ll be your instructor this semester. My contact information is here in the slide, you can also find it on canvas and you can find it on the syllabus. The big thing to be aware of is I mostly work remotely from my home in Shawnee, Kansas, which is near Kansas City.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spring &#39;23 Week 3</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week03/</guid>
      <description>Resources Slides Video Script Hello, and welcome to the week three announcements video for CC 515 in spring 2023. This week you should have milestone one completed it was due yesterday. So hopefully you&amp;rsquo;ve got that turned in. If not, please make sure you do that as soon as you can. This week, you&amp;rsquo;ll be working on the lessons for the week two module in Canvas. And then the following week, you&amp;rsquo;ll have a week to work on the second milestone, which is due Monday, February the 13th.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spring &#39;23 Week 5</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week05/</guid>
      <description>Resources Slides Video Script Hello, and welcome to the week five Announcements video for CC 515 in spring 2023. This week you should be wrapping up work on Milestone Two that was due yesterday. So hopefully you&amp;rsquo;ve got that done and turned in this week, you should start in on the week three lessons. The week three lessons will go for this week and next week and in milestone three is due in two weeks on February 27.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spring &#39;23 Week 7</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week07/</guid>
      <description>Resources Slides Video Script Hello, and welcome to the week seven Announcements video for CC 515 in spring 2023. So this month really, you should have gotten milestone three done late last week. So hopefully you&amp;rsquo;ve got that done and turned in, I&amp;rsquo;ll be grading those soon. And then for the rest of the month of March, you&amp;rsquo;ll basically be working on the week four and week five lessons, where we&amp;rsquo;re going to pivot a lot into building our own back end servers and building more Database Driven websites.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spring &#39;23 Week 9</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week09/</guid>
      <description>Resources Slides Video Script Hello, and welcome to the week nine Announcements video for CC 515 In spring 2023. So this module, you&amp;rsquo;ll be working on two things, you&amp;rsquo;ll be doing the lessons from Week Five out of the summer class, and then you&amp;rsquo;ll be working on the fourth milestone project. The modules in week five really add a lot of information to this class where we start talking about things like template rendering, we look at data serialization, we start talking about databases and routing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spring &#39;23 Week 12</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week12/</guid>
      <description>Resources Slides Video Script Hello, and welcome to the week 12 enhancements video for CC 515 in spring 2023. So you should have completed milestone for last week. So hopefully that&amp;rsquo;s going well, this week. And next week, you&amp;rsquo;ll be working on the week six lessons in Canvas, which does a lot of different things. And then you&amp;rsquo;ll have milestone five, which is due April 24.
So the week six lessons allow us to build out our web framework a little bit more deeply, we&amp;rsquo;re going to add a lot of features to our web framework, including authentication, we&amp;rsquo;re going to add interacting with some web API&amp;rsquo;s, we&amp;rsquo;re going to learn about web hooks and formal web frameworks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Previous Semesters</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/old/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/old/</guid>
      <description>Previous Semesters
Summer 2021 Week 2 Milestone 4 Milestone 5 Sessions Week 7 Summer 2022 Summer &amp;#39;22 Week 1 Summer &amp;#39;22 Week 2 Summer &amp;#39;22 Week 3 Summer &amp;#39;22 Week 4 Summer &amp;#39;22 Week 5 Summer &amp;#39;22 Week 6 Summer &amp;#39;22 Week 7 Summer &amp;#39;22 Week 8 </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>