<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>




	
	
			

	
	
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			
			

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Announcements on CIS 526 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Announcements on CIS 526 Textbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:53:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Summer &#39;22 Week 1</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week01/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Resources Slides Video Script Hello and welcome to the week one Announcements video for CIS 526 and CC 515 in summer 2022. These announcements videos are going to be a little bit more unscripted than what you&amp;rsquo;re used to. So please bear with me as I work through all this content. My name is Russell Feldhausen. And I&amp;rsquo;ll be your instructor for this semester. My contact information is shown here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summer &#39;22 Week 2</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week02/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Resources Slides Video Script Hello, and welcome to the week two announcements for CIS 526 and CC 515, in summer 2022. So this week, you should be wrapping up milestone one, which is due tonight by midnight. So make sure you get that turned in and submitted, you&amp;rsquo;ll be submitting it via GitHub. So you&amp;rsquo;ll actually post your code to GitHub classroom, make sure you make a release tag or something there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summer &#39;22 Week 3</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week03/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Resources Slides Video Script Hello, and welcome to the week three announcements video for CIS 526 and CC 515 in summer 2022. So this week you should be working on milestone two it is due tonight. So make sure you get that turned in and submitted. As before. I&amp;rsquo;ll work on getting that graded and I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about that in just a second. This week, you&amp;rsquo;ll be working on the week three lessons, those are all due on Friday.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summer &#39;22 Week 4</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week04/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Resources Slides Video Script Hello, and welcome to the week for announcements video for CIS 526 and CC 515 in summer 2022. This week you should be wrapping up milestone three, which is due tonight. So make sure you get that submitted online. And then this coming week, you&amp;rsquo;ll be working on the week four lessons. There is no milestone due this coming week, because partially we have the Fourth of July holiday on Monday.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summer &#39;22 Week 5</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week05/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Resources Slides Video Script Hello, and welcome to the week five announcements video for CIS 526 and CC 515, in summer 2022. So this week, you should be working on week five, which is the second of a two week series that leads up toward milestone four, where we really shift our focus from static websites and a little bit of Ajax in the browser to full on dynamic websites using Express and all sorts of things around that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summer &#39;22 Week 6</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week06/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Resources Slides Video Script Hello, and welcome to the week six Announcements video for CIS 527 and CC 515 in summer 2022. This week, you should be wrapping up milestone four, which is due today. So make sure you get that submitted on time and it&amp;rsquo;s ready to be graded. Then this week, you&amp;rsquo;ll be working on the week six lessons which are due this Friday. And then Monday, you&amp;rsquo;re going to have another milestone, which is milestone five.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summer &#39;22 Week 7</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week07/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Resources Slides Video Script Hello, and welcome to the week seven enhancements video for CIS 526 and CC 515 in summer 2022. So this week, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be wrapping up milestone five, which is do today&amp;rsquo;s, so make sure you get that submitted. And then we&amp;rsquo;ve got basically the week seven and eight content is all that&amp;rsquo;s left in this class. So the lessons for that are due next Monday.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summer &#39;22 Week 8</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/week08/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Resources Slides Video Script Hello, and welcome to the week eight announcements videos for CIS 526 and CC 515 in summer 2022. So this week, you should be wrapping everything up in this class, you&amp;rsquo;ve got the week seven and eight lessons which are due today, you&amp;rsquo;ve also got the milestone six, which is due on Friday, and you should be receiving TEVALs later this week. So don&amp;rsquo;t forget to fill those out as soon as you receive those.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Previous Semesters</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/old/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis526/y-announcements/old/</guid>
      <description>Previous Semesters
Summer 2021 Week 2 Milestone 4 Milestone 5 Sessions Week 7 </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>