<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Announcements :: CIS 526 Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/</link><description>Information for Current Students!
Previous Semesters Are Here</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 11:36:41 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spring '25 Week 8</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/week08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/week08/</guid><description>YouTube Video Video Script Hi, everyone, and welcome to the week eight announcements video for CIS 526 and CC 515 in spring 2025. So as we talked about last week, I’m kind of taking over this course from Dr. Bean, who’s going to be shifting over to cover another course for the rest of the semester. And so as part of that, one of the things I’ve been working on is a lot of new content for this course to introduce how you would actually build a RESTful API and a standalone single page front end application using some of the more industry standard techniques and practices.</description></item><item><title>Spring '25 Week 9</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/week09/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/week09/</guid><description>YouTube Video Video Script Hello, everybody, and welcome to the week nine announcements video for CIS 526 and CC 515 in spring 2025. Not much new to add this week. Hopefully, everybody got started on the RESTful API starter over spring break, which was due yesterday. I see that several people have already submitted this. This project is pretty easy. All you really have to do is accept the GitHub classroom and then build the starter project following exactly through my videos.</description></item><item><title>Spring '25 Week 10</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/week10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/week10/</guid><description>YouTube Video Video Script Hello and welcome to the week 10 announcements video for CIS 526 and CC 515 in spring 2025. So over spring break, we shifted over to a lot of the new content that I’ve been working on for the semester. And so I see a lot of you have already completed some of the content for weeks 8, 9 and 10, which is great. Hopefully if you’re keeping up in the class, the content for week nine adding a database was due yesterday.</description></item><item><title>Spring '25 Week 11</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/week11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/week11/</guid><description>YouTube Video Video Script Hello and welcome to the week 11 announcements video for CIS 526 and CC 515 in spring 2025. Over the weekend, I just published the materials for week 11 and week 12. So if you’re at that point and caught up, you can get started on that. Week 11 is going to add authentication to our RESTful API. So we’re going to add the ability to have background bypass authentication, as well as having CAS authentication, and we’re going to add role-based authorization to our project as well.</description></item><item><title>Spring '25 Week 12</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/week12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/week12/</guid><description>YouTube Video Video Script Hello and welcome to the week 12 announcements video for CIS 526 and CC 515 in spring 2025. I’ve got a few things I’m going to briefly cover this morning. First off, we have a guest speaker scheduled to come and talk to our class. This is going to be on Friday, April 25th at 2 o’clock p.m. Our speaker is Heather Pekrul. She is a front-end application architect at Garmin.</description></item><item><title>Spring '25 Week 13</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/week13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/week13/</guid><description>YouTube Video Video Script Hello and welcome to the week 13 announcements video for CIS 526 and CC 515 in spring 2025. So this week you should be wrapping up the front-end part one for the Vue.js. This is just kind of a simple starter project tutorial without a milestone to get you started working in Vue. It gives you some of the basic concepts of working in a Vue front-end which is a little bit different than the React front-end we worked with earlier but a lot of the concepts are still the same.</description></item><item><title>Spring '25 Week 14</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/week14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/week14/</guid><description>YouTube Video Video Script Hello, and welcome to the week 14 announcements video for CIS 526 and CC 515 in spring 2025. So we’re down here on week 14. So we’ve got some advanced topics on working with your RESTful API and view.js that you can take a look at. There’s a quick tutorial that you can run through. Mostly it’s just going through the stuff that I talk about in the textbook.</description></item><item><title>Spring '25 Week 15</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/week15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/week15/</guid><description>YouTube Video Video Script Hello and welcome to the week 15 announcements video for CIS 526 and CC 515 in spring 2025. So here we are, we’re at the last real week of the semester before finals week. Hopefully everybody was able to get through the advanced topics tutorial. Hopefully it worked really well. It’s a lot of stuff that I wanted to add at the end of the class, but didn’t really fit anywhere else.</description></item></channel></rss>