<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CSS and Text :: CIS 526 Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/b-css/10-text/index.html</link><description>As the original purpose of the World-Wide-Web was to disseminate written information, it should be no surprise that CSS would provide many properties for working with text. Some of the most commonly employed properties are:
font-family defines the font to use for the text. Its value is one or more font family or generic font names, i.e. font-family: Tahoma, serif, font-family: cursive or font-family: "Comic Sans". Font family names are typically capitalized and, if they contain spaces or special characters, double-quoted. font-size determines the size of the font. It can be a measurement or a defined value like x-small. font-style determines if the font should use its normal (default), italic, or oblique face. font-weight determines the weight (boldness) of the font. It can be normal or bold as well as lighter or darker than its parent, or specified as a numeric value between 1 and 1000. Be aware that many fonts have a limited number of weights. line-height sets the height of the line box (the distance between lines of text). It can be normal, or a numeric or percent value. text-align determines how text is aligned. Possible values are left (default), center, right, justify, along with some newer experimental values. text-indent indents the text by the specified value. text-justify is used in conjunction with text-align: justify and specifies how space should be distributed. A value of inter-word distributes space between words (appropriate for English, Spanish, Arabic, etc), and inter-character between characters (appropriate for Japanese, Chinese, etc). text-transform can be used to capitalize or lowercase text. Values include capitalize, uppercase, and lowercase. Choosing Fonts An important consideration when working with HTML text is that not all users will have the same fonts you have - and if the font is not on their system, the browser will fall back to a different option. Specifying a generic font name after a Font Family can help steer that fallback choice; for example:</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate/><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/b-css/10-text/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>