<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Previous Semesters :: CIS 526 Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/old/index.html</link><description>Previous Semesters
Spring '23 Week 1 Spring '23 Week 3 Spring '23 Week 5 Spring '23 Week 7 Spring '23 Week 9 Spring '23 Week 12 Spring '23 Week 15 Summer 2021 Week 2 Milestone 4 Milestone 5 Sessions Week 7 Summer 2022 Summer '22 Week 1 Summer '22 Week 2 Summer '22 Week 3 Summer '22 Week 4 Summer '22 Week 5 Summer '22 Week 6 Summer '22 Week 7 Summer '22 Week 8</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/old/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spring '23 Week 1</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/old/spring2023/week01/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/old/spring2023/week01/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Unknown Speaker 0:05
Hello, and welcome to the week one announcements video for CC 515 in spring 2023. My name is Russell Feldhausen. And I’ll be your instructor this semester. My contact information is here in the slide, you can also find it on canvas and you can find it on the syllabus. The big thing to be aware of is I mostly work remotely from my home in Shawnee, Kansas, which is near Kansas City. But I am on Campus, usually every Monday, this semester, most of you may be remote as well. And that’s fine, I’ll mostly meet with you via zoom, it should be pretty easy. You can contact me the easiest way to get me as russfeld@ksu.edu. But I also exist on the CS Discord server and on K State instance of Microsoft Teams, so you can find me there as well.</description></item><item><title>Spring '23 Week 3</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/old/spring2023/week03/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/old/spring2023/week03/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Hello, and welcome to the week three announcements video for CC 515 in spring 2023. This week you should have milestone one completed it was due yesterday. So hopefully you’ve got that turned in. If not, please make sure you do that as soon as you can. This week, you’ll be working on the lessons for the week two module in Canvas. And then the following week, you’ll have a week to work on the second milestone, which is due Monday, February the 13th. So the first milestone that will take care of grading this week, basically look for code comments in GitHub. And then I’ll also leave some comments in Canvas as well. If you have any comments that you want to leave for me, you can use submission comments in Canvas, or you can make release notes in GitHub for that, it may take me a little while to go through this milestone just because I really want to come through the code and make sure everything’s looking good. So please be a little patient as I go through the milestone grading. But hopefully it should be done within a week of you getting it submitted. So watch for that. And you’ll see those comments coming through on GitHub and on Canvas as soon as I get that done.</description></item><item><title>Spring '23 Week 5</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/old/spring2023/week05/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/old/spring2023/week05/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Hello, and welcome to the week five Announcements video for CC 515 in spring 2023. This week you should be wrapping up work on Milestone Two that was due yesterday. So hopefully you’ve got that done and turned in this week, you should start in on the week three lessons. The week three lessons will go for this week and next week and in milestone three is due in two weeks on February 27. So milestone grading, I will try and work on grading milestone three this week, or Milestone Two, sorry, please look for code comments and GitHub. This is one that I tend to leave quite a few comments on about code style and structure, you can always use your submission comments in Canvas, or you can use release notes and GitHub to send me any information I need to use. Please be patient, it does take me a while to get to grading this class, I know that there’s only a few students. But we’ve got a lot of things going on this semester. So I will try and get to you as soon as I can. But please look for those code comments. I’ll try and give you good feedback to help you out so you can improve for the future milestones.</description></item><item><title>Spring '23 Week 7</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/old/spring2023/week07/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/old/spring2023/week07/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Hello, and welcome to the week seven Announcements video for CC 515 in spring 2023. So this month really, you should have gotten milestone three done late last week. So hopefully you’ve got that done and turned in, I’ll be grading those soon. And then for the rest of the month of March, you’ll basically be working on the week four and week five lessons, where we’re going to pivot a lot into building our own back end servers and building more Database Driven websites. Throughout weeks four and five, you’ll be working on this large blog project as an example.</description></item><item><title>Spring '23 Week 9</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/old/spring2023/week09/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/old/spring2023/week09/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Hello, and welcome to the week nine Announcements video for CC 515 In spring 2023. So this module, you’ll be working on two things, you’ll be doing the lessons from Week Five out of the summer class, and then you’ll be working on the fourth milestone project. The modules in week five really add a lot of information to this class where we start talking about things like template rendering, we look at data serialization, we start talking about databases and routing. And then this week, you’ll start in on the blog tutorial. The blog tutorial is probably the most important part of this class because we really start building a full scale web application one bit at a time. And we go through a lot of the different ways that you can build that application and all the different manual things that you can do to deal with things like sessions and routing. And so the blog tutorial becomes really the basis that you’ll build on to build the rest of the milestones in this class.</description></item><item><title>Spring '23 Week 12</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/old/spring2023/week12/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/old/spring2023/week12/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Hello, and welcome to the week 12 enhancements video for CC 515 in spring 2023. So you should have completed milestone for last week. So hopefully that’s going well, this week. And next week, you’ll be working on the week six lessons in Canvas, which does a lot of different things. And then you’ll have milestone five, which is due April 24.</description></item><item><title>Spring '23 Week 15</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/old/spring2023/week15/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/old/spring2023/week15/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Hello, and welcome to the week 15 announcements for CC 515 In spring 2023. So this week Next, you should be completing the last module on week seven and eight content. There’s a lot of stuff going on in that module that I’ll talk about briefly. And then for the rest of the semester, your big focus is going to be on completing the last milestone in the restaurant, or in the overarching project for this semester, that last milestone is worth double the points because it’s got a lot of content in it. So make sure you’re paying close attention to that.</description></item><item><title>Summer 2021</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/old/summer2021/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/old/summer2021/index.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Summer 2022</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/old/summer2022/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis526/y-announcements/old/summer2022/index.html</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>